大家好，漂亮的人们，欢迎收看这段视频，我们将在这里开始我们的讨论
Hello you beautiful people I'm welcome to this video where we're going to be kickstarting our discussion
了解如何使用命令行删除文件和目录。
of how to delete files and directories using the command line.
在这段视频中，您将学习如何使用R.m命令删除文件，您还将
So in this video you're going to learn how to use the r.m command to delete files and you're also going
要了解如何将命令中的r与通配符一起使用以使room命令更加强大，请执行以下操作
to learn how to use the r in command along with wildcards to make the room command even more powerful
在本视频结束时，您将了解如何使用命令行删除文件，然后是下一个视频
by the end of this video you'll know how to delete files using the command line and then the next video
将把我们的讨论转移到目录上。
will move our discussion onto directories.
所以，让我们继续直截了当地谈吧。
So let's go ahead and get right into it.
好的，让我们首先在主目录中创建一个名为Delete Me的文件，这样我们就可以看到
All right so let's kick off by creating a file called Delete me in our home directory so we can see
通过查看shell提示符，我们已经在主目录中。
that we're already in a home directory by looking at the shell prompt.
我们看到Tilda在那里蠕动，这意味着当shell提示时，但为了确认，我们可以
We see the tilda the squiggle up there which means when the shell prompt but to confirm we could just
键入pdb命令print workdirectory，并看到我们确实在自己的主文件夹中。
type the PDB the command print working directory and see that we are indeed in our home folder.
那么让我们创建一个名为Delete Me的文件。
So let's create a file called delete me.
我们将使用touch命令并键入delete me并按Enter，然后如果我们使用ls命令
We're going to use the touch command and type delete me and press enter and then if we use the ls command
我们将看到，我们确实有一个名为delete me的文件，并且已经创建。
we'll see that we do indeed have a file called delete me and been created.
当然，我们可以通过打开图形文件浏览器来确认这一点，我们将看到一个名为DELETE的文件
We can confirm this of course by opening up our graphical file browser and we'll see a file called delete
我。
me.
好的，到目前为止一切都很好。
Ok so so far so good.
清除屏幕。
Clearing the screen.
既然我们已经创建了Delete Me，我们如何才能真正删除它。
Now that we've created delete me how can we actually delete it.
好的。
OK.
实际上，删除或移除该文件的方法是使用一种称为R-M命令的方法。
Well the way to actually delete or remove that file is using something called the R M command.
现在，r.m命令是。
Now the r.m command is.
我将R.M代表移除。
I will r.m stands for remove.
您所要做的就是为r.m命令提供一组指向您实际想要删除的文件的路径
And all you've got to do is give the r.m command a set of paths to files that you actually want to delete
这些可以是绝对路径，也可以是相对路径。
and these could be absolute paths or relative paths.
因此，如果我们打开r.m命令的手册页，它会显示您可以为其提供多个文件。
So if we open up the man page for the r.m command it says that you can give it more than one file.
好的，你看，你可以给它一个文件，然后它后面有三个点。
Ok you see you can give it a file and then it's got three dots after it.
从我们对命令行语法或命令行布局的讨论中我们知道，这三个点
And we know from our discussion of command line syntax or command line layout that these three dots
意思是你可以有不止一个。
mean you can have more than one.
如果您需要复习一下上一节的小抄，它已经提供了所有的信息
And if you need a refresher on that check the cheat sheet in the previous section it's got all the information
在那里等着你。
there for you.
所以让我们继续删除，删除我，这样我就可以了，因为我已经在同一个文件夹中了。
So let's go ahead and remove delete me so I could because I'm already in the same folder.
我可以，你知道，就像这样使用相对路径。
I could just you know use the relative path like that.
R.M.删除我。
R.m delete me.
当我按Enter键时，我们将看到Delete Me确实已被删除。
And when I press Enter we'll see that delete me has indeed been deleted.
我可以，如果我创建了删除我，如果我创建了删除我，这次在我们的Documents文件夹中删除我。
I could if I create delete me if I create delete me in our documents folder this time.
好的。
OK.
因此，如果我查看我们的Documents文件夹，我们会发现在命令中的那一分钟已经创建了Delete Me
So if I look in our documents folder we see delete me has been created at the minute in the command
排队。
line.
我只是在主文件夹里。
I'm just in the home folder.
所以如果我试图做R.M删除我，那是行不通的，因为这里没有删除我这样的东西
So if I tried to do r.m delete me that won't work because there is no such thing as delete me in this
在此目录中。
in this directory.
那就把它删掉吧。
So delete it.
我得做所有RAM文档。
I have to do all RAM documents.
劈开删除我，所以我必须给它相对于我们现在所在位置的路径，也就是主文件夹。
Slash delete me so I have to give it the path relative to where we are now which is the home folder.
所以在这里我在沃达得到删除我的文件后，然后删除我。
So here I am in Voda to get to delete me after documents then delete me.
好的，所以文档只需删除我，我按Enter键，然后它就被删除了。
OK so documents just delete me and I press enter and then it gets deleted.
好的。
OK.
而且你可以有不止一个。
And you can have more than one.
所以如果我继续创建一个名为的文件，比方说，为一个DirectX创建一个文件。
So if I go ahead and create a file called let's say for one directx.
那在我们的主目录里。
That's in our home directory.
我在我们的文档中创建了一个名为Faltu的文件，因此需要接收我们的文档和名为
I create a file called Faltu in our documents so fall to take in our documents and a credit for called
在我们的下载中有三个点的滴答声。
for three dot tickety in our downloads.
就像我说的，我在家里的文件夹里有一个。
Like I say I've got one in the home folder.
一份文档和一份下载中的文档。
One of the documents and one in downloads.
好的，几乎所有这些，我都可以一个接一个地输入，所以我对一个文本做了R.M。
OK so nearly all those I can just enter them one after another so I do r.m for one text.
我不需要因为那件事做任何事。
I don't have to do anything because of that.
这样就可以了，因为我已经在主目录中，与其文档劈开、法尔图和
That will do because I'm already in the home directory the same folder as it documents slash Faltu and
下载劈开文件3。
downloads slash file 3.
如果我或者你看到一份失踪的文件，福尔图已经从文件中消失了，4：03已经消失了。
If I Precentor you see the file one disappeared Faltu has disappeared from documents and 4:03 has disappeared
从下载中下载。
from downloads.
因此，DRM命令是用于文件的非常简单的命令。
So DRM command is a very simple command to use for files.
只要把它想象成触摸命令的对立面就行了。
Just think of it as the opposite of the touch command.
如果你想创建一个文件，你确实接触到了外来的文件，你已经想要删除它了。
If you want to create a file you do touch foreign one you want to delete it already.
R.M远一点，它就会像那样工作。
R.m far one and it will work just like that.
因此，不管我们是否已经了解了如何基本地使用auum命令，让我们将其提升一个档次，并使用它
So whether we've seen how to use the Aurum command in a basic way let's take it up a notch and use it
以及通配符。
along with wildcards.
现在，通配符可以真正提升命令的功能。
Now wildcards can really level up the power that your commands have.
让我们来看看我们是如何使用R M命令来做这件事的。
So let's just see see how we do this using the R M command.
我们来做几个新文件吧。
Let's make a few new files.
让我们创建一个1.60规格的Faltu dot PMG和4：03 dot jp G的文件。
Let's make a file 1.60 spec Faltu dot PMG and 4:03 dot JP G.
因此，当我按Enter键时，您会看到这三个文件都已在我们的主文件夹中创建。
So when I press enter you see that all three of those have been created in our home folder.
好的，现在我们如何删除以datti xti结尾的每一个。
OK now how would we delete every single one of them that ended in Datti XTi.
所以这实际上只是狂热地为达蒂·西蒂的案子做了另一个文件。
So that's actually just fanatic's make another one file for Datti XTi case.
我们到了DirectX Take的末尾，我们有一个以PNB和GBG结尾的。
We've got to the end in directx take and we've got one that ends in PNB and GBG.
我们怎么删除它们呢。
How would we delete them.
他们就是我最终来到这里的人。
They're the ones I ended up here.
嗯，首先我们可以手工做。
Well first of all we could do it manually.
我们可以说我们的M-FILE赢得了60名医生，而对于40名医生来说，这实际上是可行的。
We could say our M-file won doctor 60 and for 40 actually that would work.
但我想要一个比这更聪明的解决方案。
But I want a bit more of a clever solution than that.
我想说删除所有以点T x T结尾的文件。
I want to say delete every file that ends in Dot T x T.
现在我们这样做的方式是给命令一个模式，任何与此模式匹配的都将
Now the way we do that is by giving the command a pattern and anything that matches this pattern will
作为命令行参数添加到它。
be added as a command line argument to it.
所以如果我要用的图案是这颗星Datti XTi。
So if the pattern that I'm going to use is this star Datti XTi.
现在我们来分析一下这个。
Now let's break this down.
好的，那么这颗星有任何意义。
OK so the star means anything.
任何东西都可以去那里。
Anything could go there.
所以这整件事就是我们的模式。
So this whole thing is our pattern.
好的，开始有任何意义，然后是达蒂XTi。
OK the start means anything and then Datti XTi.
因此，这意味着任何与该模式匹配的东西，它都必须做的是，在Datti XTi中，它是正确的。
So what this means is for anything to match that pattern at all it has to do is and in Datti XTi right.
基本上，这是说删除所有以点XTi结尾的内容，然后按Enter键。
So basically what this is saying is remove everything that ends in Dot XTi and we press enter on that.
你看秋天的和Fall For都被删除了，因为它们以点结尾。
You see the fall one and fall for have been deleted because they ended in Dot.
T x T。
T x t.
好的，让我们试着看看能不能用其他力量使这个Make文件再一次达到1.60，
OK so let's let's try and see if we could make some other forces make this make file 1.60 again and
爱上DOT T。
fall for the DOT T.
我们回过头来做这些吧。
Let's make those back then.
那么让我们创建一些文件。
Then let's let's create some of the files.
就是创建一些叫做崇高圆点x，t和圆圈的问题。
Is create some called Sublime Dotti x t and the circlets problem one right and then blam to.
PMG和崇高三大顶级JPT。
PMG and sublime three top JPT.
所以我们有一些以问题开头的，还有一些以Word文件开头的。
So we've got some that start with problem and some that start with the Word file.
好的，我们如何删除那些只以Word文件开头的。
OK how would we delete the ones that just start with the word file.
我们这样做的方式是，我们用r来指挥。
Well the way that we do this is we would use the r in command.
当然，同样，因为我们需要删除，所以我们需要给它另一个Potten。
Again of course because we need to delete then we need to give it another Potten.
因此，让我们考虑一下，我们将如何创建一个与任何内容匹配的模式，只要它以
So let's think how would we create a pattern that would match anything as long as it started with the
Word文件。
word file.
我们可以做到这一点的方法是，我们可以提取单词file，然后加上一个星号，因为这意味着
Well the way we can do that is we can take the word file and then put a star because this means as long
因为它以file开头，然后是后面的任何内容，所以它是匹配的。
as it starts with file and then has anything after it it matches.
所以它所要做的就是从Word文件开始。
So all it has to do is start with the word file.
如果我按Enter键，我们会看到文件1、2、3和4，您知道的关于该文件的文本无关紧要
And if I press Enter we see the file 1 2 3 and 4 that text that you know doesn't matter about the file
扩展名或任何东西，只要它们以文件开头，它们就被删除了。
extension or anything as long as they start with file they've been deleted.
但是所有的沙巴农场都保留在那里。
But all of the Shebaa farms have been kept there.
好的。
OK.
让我们再次创建4、1、2、3和4，因此我们将为1.60Faltu点PMG创建Touch
So let's let's create 4 1 2 3 and 4 again so we're going to create touch for 1.60 Faltu dot PMG for
3.0 JPT和4 JPT给XTi博士，我们会再把它们做回来的。
3.0 JPT and 4 for Dr. XTi we'll make them back again.
好的。
OK.
现在，我们要删除其中包含数字2的所有文件。
Now we want to delete all of the files that have the number two in them.
好的。
OK.
那我们该怎么做呢。
So how would we do that.
我们可以做的是，我们可能会说，好的，我们把它去掉。
Well what we might do is we might say OK let's remove.
它从什么开始并不重要，但必须有两个人在那里，在哪里也不重要
It doesn't matter what it starts with but it's got to have the two in there and it doesn't matter where
它的结尾是。
it ends in.
好的，所以我们在这里，我们说它可以有任何东西，然后是数字2，然后是后面的任何东西。
OK so here we are we're saying it could have anything then the number two and then anything afterwards.
因为如果我们这样做，我们会看到法尔图已经被删除，鞋黑2也被删除了，但是所有的
Because if we do that we see the Faltu has been deleted and shoeblack 2 has been deleted but all the
其他人都很好。
others are OK.
去掉那些以点杰皮结尾的怎么样？
What about getting rid of the ones that end in dot Jaypee.
要做到这一点，使用所有RAM结束在Doc Jaypee中，我按Enter键获取三个JPT和SUPEME三个
Well to do that used to all RAM ends in Doc Jaypee I press enter for three JPT and sublime three have
已被删除。
been deleted.
其他人和何西蒂医生都还在那里。
All the others and the doctor he XTi are still there.
删除那些R.M所有以Doctor XTi结尾的内容如何？按Enter键。
What about deleting those r.m everything that ends in Doctor XTi press enter.
它们也都被删除了。
And they've all been deleted as well.
因此您可以在这里看到通配符如何真正使您的命令变得更加强大
So you can see here how wild cards can really make the the your commands a whole lot more powerful and
具体得多。
a lot more specific.
还有一件事我想给你们看，我们上去吧。
There's one more that I want to show you let's just go up here.
我们已经找回了我们的文件，让我们把火山灰喷出的问题文件也弄回来吧，PMG博士。
We've made back our files and let's make back ash blam problem files problem too doc PMG.
我认为和崇高的三个顶尖的JPT。
I think and sublime three top JPT.
好的。
OK.
现在，如果我们想去掉里面有两到三个的那些怎么办？
Now what if we wanted to get rid of the ones that had two or three in them.
你还记得我们是怎么到那个有两个人的地方的吗？
Well do you remember how we got to the one that had two in it.
正确的。
Right.
我们说它可以以任何形式开始，然后必须以任何形式结束。
We said it could start with anything then have to end in anything.
现在我们想给它一些选择。
Well now we want to give it some options.
这就是方括号的用武之地。
And this is where the square brackets come in.
到目前为止，他说。
So far he said.
好的。
OK.
类似的东西，但是说它可以以任何东西开始，然后有两个或三个，然后结束
Something like that but saying it could start with anything then have either two or three and then ending
什么都行。
anything.
所以要去掉四、二、四、三，升华二、三。
So they should get rid of four two four three and sublime two and three.
因此，如果震源法尔图和秋天三和问题二和三已经被删除。
So if hypocenter Faltu and fall three and problem two and three have been deleted.
所以通配符是令人难以置信的工具，它真正允许您控制当您使用
So wild cards are incredible tools that really allow you to control what's going on when you use your
命令和任何与此模式匹配的内容都将作为命令行参数传递给命令
commands and anything that matches this pattern will be passed as a command line arguments to the command
你用通配符来做的事。
that you use the wild cards for.
所以这也是一些通配符在起作用。
So that's a bit of wildcards in action as well.
在这个视频中，您可以了解到r.m命令，r.m命令就是该命令
So there you have it in this video you learn about the r.m command that the r.m command is the command
用于从您的文件系统中删除内容。
that's used to remove stuff from your file system.
在这段视频中，我们特别关注删除文件。
And in this video we focus specifically on deleting files.
您还在上一个视频中学到的通配符的基础上进行了构建，并看到了通配符的使用
You also built upon what you learned in the last video about wildcards and saw wild cards being used
在删除文件的行动中。
in action to delete files.
现在，您在本视频中看到的通配符不仅仅适用于r.m命令。
Now what you saw about wildcards in this video it doesn't only apply to the r.m command.
您编写的有关通配符以及如何执行特定任务的内容适用于任何命令。
What you wrote about wildcards and how you might do specific tasks works for any command.
您使用通配符构建称为正则表达式的模式，与这些模式匹配的任何内容都是
You build patterns called regular expressions with wildcards and whatever matches those patterns is
作为命令行参数传递给您正在使用的命令。
passed as a command line argument to the command that you're using.
因此，您已经在练习中看到了一些外卡。
So there you are you've seen some wild cards in practice as well.
接下来我们要做的是，我们会更深入地展开这场讨论，我
Up next what we're going to be doing is we're going to be developing this discussion a bit more I'm
接下来我们来看看如何删除目录。
going to move on to looking at how you might delete directories.
你怎么能删除文件夹呢。
How can you delete folders.
所以这是一个完全是下一个层次的东西，它可以是非常聪明的。
So that's a that's a completely next level it can be very smart and stuff.
那么在下一个视频中再见吧。
So see you in the next video.